SimpleText is the native text editor for the Apple classic Mac OS. SimpleText allows editing including 
text formatting (underline, italic, bold, etc.), fonts, and sizes. It was developed to integrate the 
features included in the different versions of TeachText that were created by various software 
development groups within Apple. 

It can be considered similar to Windows' WordPad application. In later versions it also gained 
additional read only display capabilities for PICT files, as well as other Mac OS built-in formats like 
Quickdraw GX and QTIF, 3DMF and even QuickTime movies. SimpleText can even record short sound 
samples and, using Apple's PlainTalk speech system, read out text in English. Users who wanted to 
add sounds longer than 24 seconds, however, needed to use a separate program to create the sound 
and then paste the desired sound into the document using ResEdit. 

SimpleText superseded TeachText, which was included in System Software up until Mac OS 8. The 
need for SimpleText arose after Apple stopped bundling MacWrite, to ensure that every user could 
open and read Readme documents. 

The key improvement between SimpleText and TeachText was the addition of text styling. 
SimpleText could support multiple fonts and font sizes, while TeachText supported only a single font 
per document. Adding text styling features made SimpleText WorldScript-savvy, meaning that it can 
use Simplified and Traditional Chinese characters. Like TeachText, SimpleText was also limited to 
only 32 kB of text in a document, although images could increase the total file size beyond this limit. 
SimpleText style information was stored in the file's resource fork in such a way that if the resource 
fork was stripped (such as by uploading to a non-Macintosh server), the text information would be 
retained. 
